<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Atari and Retro Site of Goz - goz</title><link href="https://gtia.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://gtia.com/feeds/goz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://gtia.com/</id><updated>2020-05-27T10:43:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>WFH - PowerBook G4</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/05/27/wfh-powerbook-g4/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-27T10:43:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-27T10:43:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-05-27:/2020/05/27/wfh-powerbook-g4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I didn't change out the &lt;a href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/27/work-from-home-continues-with-my-macintosh-se-30/"&gt;Mac SE/30&lt;/a&gt; for a couple of weeks, but for this week I dug out one of my favorite laptops, the Apple PowerBook G4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PowerBook G4" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/wfhPBG4-2020-05-27-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 00s I used a 15" PowerBook G4 and had access to the 12" iBooks, but never got to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I didn't change out the &lt;a href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/27/work-from-home-continues-with-my-macintosh-se-30/"&gt;Mac SE/30&lt;/a&gt; for a couple of weeks, but for this week I dug out one of my favorite laptops, the Apple PowerBook G4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PowerBook G4" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/wfhPBG4-2020-05-27-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 00s I used a 15" PowerBook G4 and had access to the 12" iBooks, but never got to really use the 12" PowerBook G4. I have been watching eBay auctions and finally picked up this beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the form factor of the 12" PowerBooks. It would be amazing if a company offered a laptop like this today. The screen has a matte finish, so it's not like I'm looking in a mirror, and I really like the 4:3 aspect ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using it for working for home almost feels like it's cheating. Although surfing the internet is painful, iTerm runs well on it making it a great CLI terminal. The keyboard is a little stiff, it really gives your fingers a workout. I may leave it out for a couple of weeks...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="mac"></category><category term="apple"></category><category term="wfh"></category></entry><entry><title>Work from home continues with my Macintosh SE/30</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/27/work-from-home-continues-with-my-macintosh-se-30/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-27T17:56:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T17:56:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-04-27:/2020/04/27/work-from-home-continues-with-my-macintosh-se-30/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week at home, another retro terminal to work from, my 128MB Macintosh SE/30!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mac SE/30 Work From Home Setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/se30wfh-2020-04-27-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've talked about this bad boy a lot in the last few months. It's such a workhorse, and everytime I get on it I'm transported to 1990. The terminal I'm using is Zterm, which works …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week at home, another retro terminal to work from, my 128MB Macintosh SE/30!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mac SE/30 Work From Home Setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/se30wfh-2020-04-27-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've talked about this bad boy a lot in the last few months. It's such a workhorse, and everytime I get on it I'm transported to 1990. The terminal I'm using is Zterm, which works incredibly well. I haven't had any issues with it as a terminal to a Linux box. On the Linux box I use tmux as a terminal multiplexer, and it just works with Zterm's emulation. Emoji and unicode characters cause a little screen corruption, but that's understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For writing, I use Vim for everything, so I'm not missing anything writing on the SE/30. In fact, this article is being written on the SE/30. I've thought about downloading the files, working with a native editor, and uploading, but that seems like a lot of work. That being said, I need to do it or I risk giving up my Geek card!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Editing in Microsoft Word 4.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used Zmodem to download this blog post and continued editing the file in Microsoft Word 4.0. I haven't really explored word processors for System 7.1. I can't remember what I used back then... ClarisWorks maybe? It's amazing how I don't remember a lot of the software I used on my Powerbook 100. If I could get it to start I could check. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing the document in Word and sending it back over to Vim worked better than I thought it would. Only issue was the first time I saved it I didn't change the format to text. After I did that, the file transferred fine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="wfh"></category><category term="mac"></category><category term="se30"></category></entry><entry><title>Using my MegaSTe for another week of working from home</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/19/using-my-megaste-for-another-week-of-working-from-home/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-19T18:43:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-19T18:43:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-04-19:/2020/04/19/using-my-megaste-for-another-week-of-working-from-home/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My retro computer for this week is my MegaSTe. I chose it mainly because of &lt;a href="TK"&gt;pizza week&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href="TK"&gt;/r/RetroBattlestations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My MegaSTe running Uniterm" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/MegaSTeWFH-2020-04-19-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not quite sure when and where I picked up this MegaSTe. It probably came from eBay. I really wanted an STe model, and then I stumbled oupon this …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My retro computer for this week is my MegaSTe. I chose it mainly because of &lt;a href="TK"&gt;pizza week&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href="TK"&gt;/r/RetroBattlestations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My MegaSTe running Uniterm" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/MegaSTeWFH-2020-04-19-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not quite sure when and where I picked up this MegaSTe. It probably came from eBay. I really wanted an STe model, and then I stumbled oupon this machine. All of the greatness of the STe with the added bonus of a 16MHz clockspeed and an internal hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MegaSTe borrowed it's style from the TT, leaving the Mega ST style behind. It's a very interesting looking machine, and a lot better looking than most of the machines from the early 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm using the SC1224 monitor that I got with my 1040STf back in '88. It still works very well, no complaints whatsoever. A Reddit user pointed out that the keyboard is not a MegaSTe keyboard. I researched it a little bit, and the first models of the MegaSTe came with keyboards from the MegaST line. This is one of the best feeling keyboards I have ever used. I may have to find a place to leave this hooked up so I can use it for writing more often!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, the better news is that &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/retrobattlestations/comments/g4g84e/pizza_week_a_specialty_pizza_to_rise_above_the/"&gt;I won the Pizza Week contest for having More Than Pepperoni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="wfh"></category><category term="atari"></category><category term="megaste"></category></entry><entry><title>Working from home on the iMac G4</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/18/working-from-home-on-the-imac-g4/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-18T09:39:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-18T09:39:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-04-18:/2020/04/18/working-from-home-on-the-imac-g4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week working from home, another week with a piece of retro equipment. The iMac G4 mamay not technically be retro, but I believe it is old enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="iMac G4 Work from Home" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/imacwfh-2020-04-14-800x.jpeg"&gt;
This particular model was bought during the OS X 10.3 release party at the Apple Store. Since then I've upgraded the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week working from home, another week with a piece of retro equipment. The iMac G4 mamay not technically be retro, but I believe it is old enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="iMac G4 Work from Home" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/imacwfh-2020-04-14-800x.jpeg"&gt;
This particular model was bought during the OS X 10.3 release party at the Apple Store. Since then I've upgraded the RAM to 2GB and installed an SSD. Performance is pretty great, I can run the G5 Garageband demos with ease. The OS is Mac OS X 10.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iMac makes a great terminal, there is an older version of iTerm that runs on it. Fonts are still the same so I can install my current favorite font, &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/lp/mono/"&gt;JetBrains Mono&lt;/a&gt;. Apple introduced &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaces_(software)"&gt;Spaces&lt;/a&gt; in 10.5, giving me virtual desktops. &lt;a href="https://www.floodgap.com/software/tenfourfox/"&gt;TenFourFox&lt;/a&gt; works well enough for minor browsing duties, I used it mainly to look at pictures that were posted to IRC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="wfh"></category><category term="imacg4"></category></entry><entry><title>Last week's WFH setup</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/13/last-week-s-wfh-setup/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-13T09:17:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T09:17:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-04-13:/2020/04/13/last-week-s-wfh-setup/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For last week I decided to dig out one of my VT420 terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VT420 WFH Setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/wfhvt420a-2020-04-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular terminal was picked up from a school auction back in the late 90s or early 00s. I remember looking at the terminals they had for sale at the start of the day when they were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For last week I decided to dig out one of my VT420 terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VT420 WFH Setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/wfhvt420a-2020-04-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular terminal was picked up from a school auction back in the late 90s or early 00s. I remember looking at the terminals they had for sale at the start of the day when they were priced at $2.00. Luckily, I couldn't make a decision until the end of the day. By that time the terminals were marked down to $1.00, so I bought two of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terminals were stored along with my remaining retro hardware, waiting to be used. The problem was that I didn't have the right cable to plug into the offset 6-pin MMJ connector. In the fall of 2018 I finally broke down and searched the internet for the correct adapters. &lt;a href="http://www.pacificcable.com/Picture_Page.asp?DataName=BC16E"&gt;Pacific Custom Cable&lt;/a&gt; had the offset cables, and eBay had a couple of the offset 25 pin RS232 adapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the terminal with my Lucent Portmaster a couple of times, but now I use it with my &lt;a href="https://gtia.com/2019/10/23/setting-up-a-wifi-modem-with-the-chip-computer/"&gt;homemade WIFI modem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="wfh"></category><category term="vt420"></category></entry></feed>