<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Atari and Retro Site of Goz - goz</title><link href="https://gtia.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://gtia.com/feeds/goz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://gtia.com/</id><updated>2020-04-18T09:39:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Working from home on the iMac G4</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/18/working-from-home-on-the-imac-g4/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-18T09:39:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-18T09:39:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-04-18:/2020/04/18/working-from-home-on-the-imac-g4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week working from home, another week with a piece of retro equipment. The iMac G4 mamay not technically be retro, but I believe it is old enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="iMac G4 Work from Home" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/imacwfh-2020-04-14-800x.jpeg"&gt;
This particular model was bought during the OS X 10.3 release party at the Apple Store. Since then I've upgraded the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week working from home, another week with a piece of retro equipment. The iMac G4 mamay not technically be retro, but I believe it is old enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="iMac G4 Work from Home" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/imacwfh-2020-04-14-800x.jpeg"&gt;
This particular model was bought during the OS X 10.3 release party at the Apple Store. Since then I've upgraded the RAM to 2GB and installed an SSD. Performance is pretty great, I can run the G5 Garageband demos with ease. The OS is Mac OS X 10.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iMac makes a great terminal, there is an older version of iTerm that runs on it. Fonts are still the same so I can install my current favorite font, &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/lp/mono/"&gt;JetBrains Mono&lt;/a&gt;. Apple introduced [Spaces](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaces_(software) in 10.5, giving me virtual desktops. &lt;a href="https://www.floodgap.com/software/tenfourfox/"&gt;TenFourFox&lt;/a&gt; works well enough for minor browsing duties, I used it mainly to look at pictures that were posted to IRC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="wfh"></category><category term="imacg4"></category></entry><entry><title>Last week's WFH setup</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2020/04/13/last-week-s-wfh-setup/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-13T09:17:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T09:17:00-04:00</updated><author><name>goz</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2020-04-13:/2020/04/13/last-week-s-wfh-setup/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For last week I decided to dig out one of my VT420 terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VT420 WFH Setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/wfhvt420a-2020-04-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular terminal was picked up from a school auction back in the late 90s or early 00s. I remember looking at the terminals they had for sale at the start of the day when they were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For last week I decided to dig out one of my VT420 terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VT420 WFH Setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/wfhvt420a-2020-04-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular terminal was picked up from a school auction back in the late 90s or early 00s. I remember looking at the terminals they had for sale at the start of the day when they were priced at $2.00. Luckily, I couldn't make a decision until the end of the day. By that time the terminals were marked down to $1.00, so I bought two of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terminals were stored along with my remaining retro hardware, waiting to be used. The problem was that I didn't have the right cable to plug into the offset 6-pin MMJ connector. In the fall of 2018 I finally broke down and searched the internet for the correct adapters. &lt;a href="http://www.pacificcable.com/Picture_Page.asp?DataName=BC16E"&gt;Pacific Custom Cable&lt;/a&gt; had the offset cables, and eBay had a couple of the offset 25 pin RS232 adapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the terminal with my Lucent Portmaster a couple of times, but now I use it with my &lt;a href="https://gtia.com/2019/10/23/setting-up-a-wifi-modem-with-the-chip-computer/"&gt;homemade WIFI modem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="wfh"></category><category term="vt420"></category></entry></feed>