<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>GozAtari8</title><link href="http://gtia.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://gtia.com/feeds/hardware.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://gtia.com/</id><updated>2015-12-28T23:22:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>VBXE to GBS-8200 to VGA monitor is a success</title><link href="http://gtia.com/2015/12/28/vbxe-to-gbs-8200-to-vga-monitor-is-a-success/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-12-28T23:22:00+01:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2015-12-28:2015/12/28/vbxe-to-gbs-8200-to-vga-monitor-is-a-success/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After much troubleshooting, I now have VGA output from an 800XL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VBXE in Action" src="http://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2015/IMG_9078-2.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VBXE plugs into the 5 pin connector on the GBS-8200, which then goes out as VGA. Unfortunately, the Apple monitor doesn't have a VGA plug, so I have an adapter to convert it. Looks very good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to install a Ultimate 1MB and the stereo upgrade...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="vbxe"></category><category term="vga"></category></entry><entry><title>The original Xbox is an awesome emulator machine</title><link href="http://gtia.com/2014/11/15/the-xbox-is-an-awesome-emulator-machine/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-11-15T13:45:00+01:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2014-11-15:2014/11/15/the-xbox-is-an-awesome-emulator-machine/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I modded my Xbox a long time ago, and over the years forgot about it, leaving the Xbox to sit on the bottom shelf. It waited patiently for years until I stumbled across a post on AtariAge about using the Xbox with emulators that piqued my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon firing up the Xbox, I was surprised that it was still functional. Well, sort of. It usually took a few tries to fire up. I installed a larger hard drive in it and grabbed AtariXLBox from &lt;a href="http://xport.xbox-scene.com/"&gt;Xport&lt;/a&gt; along with a bunch of A8 games in various formats. It was able to play all of them without a hitch. In fact, with the Xbox plugged into a CRT TV, it was pretty much indistinguishable from the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a big emulation person, I’d rather be playing on the real thing, but using an Xbox has it’s advantages. For one, I can easily take it places and play several systems on it (there are emulators for all of the major consoles and arcade). It doesn’t support the multi-joy adapter from what I’ve seen, but I should be able to set up the 3rd joypad to work as the third player in Dynakillers. Lastly, it does support saving the settings on a game-by-game basis which makes it easier to start games up without worrying about what hardware the game requires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be relatively inexpensive to try out this route. An original Xbox usually goes for under $50 on eBay, but if you look at garage sales or Craigslist you can probably find it cheaper. You’ll need to do some research on how to mod the Xbox so you can run the emulators. This usually involves using certain games with certain save files that trick the Xbox into running unsigned code. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="xbox"></category><category term="emulation"></category></entry><entry><title>Fired up my Colecovision Adam for the first time</title><link href="http://gtia.com/2014/05/12/fired-up-my-colecovision-adam-for-the-first-time/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-12T11:56:00+02:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2014-05-12:2014/05/12/fired-up-my-colecovision-adam-for-the-first-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At some time I picked up a Colecovision Adam (complete) with several books and datapacks. I was disappointed Donkey Kong wasn't in the box, but Donkey Kong Jr. was. As I was cleaning and arranging my basement lab, I decided I had better at least try out the Colecovision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first turn it on, you are put into some sort of typewriter mode. I don't have a ribbon in the printer, and the print head didn't like being turned on. Eventually, the printer stopped jamming the print head to the side, and I could type in the typewriter. I then switched it to word processing mode. Unless I'm missing something, this mode was terrible. This came out the same year as AtariWriter was released, and it doesn't even have full screen editing. I would have hated to actually use this to word process. That is, unless I'm missing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was to try out the data packs. They look like normal audio cassettes, but work like the tape back up drives I used to use at work. I put Donkey Kong into the unity, and hit the reset slider besides the cartridge port (luckily I had the manual :-). And there I was playing DK Jr! Unfortunately, while it looks good, it doesn't play very much like the original. The chomping creatures (I'm sure they have a name) move too slow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I'm glad to have a piece of history, and will be happy to put this into my future antique electronics store!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="colecovision"></category><category term="adam"></category></entry><entry><title>Upgraded a XF551 disk drive to a 3.5" drive</title><link href="http://gtia.com/2014/05/05/upgraded-a-xf551-disk-drive-to-a-35-drive/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-05T13:03:13+02:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2014-05-05:2014/05/05/upgraded-a-xf551-disk-drive-to-a-35-drive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 90s I purchased a large Atari collection on eBay. It's been sitting in storage, just waiting for me to dig into it. I remember I bough it for the Spartados X cartridge and R-time 8, but didn't realize everything else that was in it. I found an XF551 case which apparently had a CSS 3.5" upgrade kit installed. After stealing a 3.5" drive mechanism from an old PC, I was able to format my first 3.5" disk on my trusty Atari 800XL! (Actually, it took me 4 tries to find a disk that would format. I was using an ST to format a disk first to make sure it wasn't the upgrade causing the formatting to fail.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't know what I'm going to use floppy disks for, but it is still pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My XF351!" src="http://cdn.gtia.com/2014/xf551-3.5-l.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="xf551"></category><category term="diskdrive"></category></entry></feed>