<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>GozAtari8 - Hardware</title><link href="https://gtia.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://gtia.com/feeds/hardware.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://gtia.com/</id><updated>2019-09-30T11:03:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Visiting Vintage Computer Fest Midwest 14 (2019)</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2019/09/30/visiting-vintage-computer-fest-midwest-14-2019-/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-30T11:03:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-30T11:03:00+02:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2019-09-30:/2019/09/30/visiting-vintage-computer-fest-midwest-14-2019-/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Welcome banner" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/WelcomeBanner-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past September I had the opportunity to make it to my second Vintage ComputerFest - Midwest. It was a great opportunity to not only see a lot of great hardware and software, but to also hang out with others that are as passionate about retro computing as I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Welcome banner" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/WelcomeBanner-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past September I had the opportunity to make it to my second Vintage ComputerFest - Midwest. It was a great opportunity to not only see a lot of great hardware and software, but to also hang out with others that are as passionate about retro computing as I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The facility was a lot bigger this year, with three large ballrooms and a vendor area in the large hallway. My biggest complaint is the HVAC, two of the rooms were freezing while the third was barely comfortable. The PA was also a little annoying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Atari Forever!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Room B" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/RoomB-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I arrived after my 5 hour drive I headed straight to the bathroom. But, after that, it was time to hit the Atari area. And the Atari area did not disappoint. MoparStephen had brought in a ton of Goodies, including an Atari800 with Incognito, an Eclaire XL, an 1088XEL and the greatest Atari 8-bit computer to date, the 1088XLD. The 1088XEL and 1088XLD are MyTek's re-imagining of the Atari 8-bit computer's motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MoparStephen's table" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/MoparStephenAtari-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slor was also there with a very impressive Atari display plus extras, with a couple of Tandy computers thrown in for good measure. I spent a lot of time play testing the new version of Atarinet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SCAT Atari user group had a nice set up, including some awesome sounding games and demos playing. There were also a smattering of Ataris through out the complex. I didn't do a count, but it appears that there were more Ataris setup than any other computer brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ben Heck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ben Heck's portable Atari 800" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/BenHeckPortable800-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you following the maker or building scene, you've probably seen Ben Heck's creation. Well, he was at VCFMW, and set up with the Atari people. He was showing off some very cool things, but the coolest was his newest Atari 800 handheld. I had missed his video when he originally built it, but I'm kinda glad to have been surprised with it. The portable Atari 800 works very well, and very fun to play with. Hanging out with Ben Heck was really cool too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;David Murray (The 8-Bit Guy) and the Commander X16&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Me and the 8-bit guy" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/MeAndThe8BitGuy-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in the Atari area was the prototype of the Commander X16, the 8-bit guy's ultimate 8-bit computer. Even in this unfinished form the computer was pretty impressive, especially with what it was capable of at only 2MHz. I've already subscribed to his Youtube channel so I can keep abreast of Commander X16 updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I would have gotten a chance to talk to him more, but he was understandably very popular. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Odds and ends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most surprising take away from VCFMW was the surprising lack of Apple II hardware. There were a couple of Apple IIs here and there, and a fully kitted IIgs, but nothing compared to what the Atari people were showing off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Full on Apple IIgs" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2019/IIgs-2019-10-01-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really good time, and I hope I get a chance to go next year. If I do get to go, I'm going to bring some things to show off. What, you may ask? I don't know yet... Maybe I'll finally complete a game I would like to show off. :-) Or, something Apple II related!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also &lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/iR3Gd2Wb13TtUQqP6"&gt;took a bunch of photos and placed them up on Google Photos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vcfmw"></category><category term="retro"></category></entry><entry><title>Bummer, the last day of Christmas break</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2019/01/02/bummer-the-last-day-of-christmas-break/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-02T15:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-02T15:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2019-01-02:/2019/01/02/bummer-the-last-day-of-christmas-break/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty bummed. It's the last day of break and I didn't even get a chance to start &lt;a href="http://gtia.com/2018/12/07/christmas-break-project-upgrading-my-b-key-atari-400-with-48-52k-of-ram-and-the-super-color-cpu-card/"&gt;on my big project&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe I'll get a chance to finish it before next year....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I do have the parts now to build &lt;a href="https://github.com/kbr-net/sdrive-max"&gt;an SDrive Max&lt;/a&gt;. The SDrive …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty bummed. It's the last day of break and I didn't even get a chance to start &lt;a href="http://gtia.com/2018/12/07/christmas-break-project-upgrading-my-b-key-atari-400-with-48-52k-of-ram-and-the-super-color-cpu-card/"&gt;on my big project&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe I'll get a chance to finish it before next year....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I do have the parts now to build &lt;a href="https://github.com/kbr-net/sdrive-max"&gt;an SDrive Max&lt;/a&gt;. The SDrive Max is an Arduino base floppy disk and tape emulator that can be used with the Atari 8-bit computers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="sdrivemax"></category><category term="supercolorcpucard"></category><category term="400"></category></entry><entry><title>Christmas break project - Upgrading my B-Key Atari 400 with 48/52K of RAM and the Super Color CPU card</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2018/12/07/christmas-break-project-upgrading-my-b-key-atari-400-with-48-52k-of-ram-and-the-super-color-cpu-card/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-07T20:49:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-07T20:49:00+01:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2018-12-07:/2018/12/07/christmas-break-project-upgrading-my-b-key-atari-400-with-48-52k-of-ram-and-the-super-color-cpu-card/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past year I took a chance on an eBay auction that featured an Atari 400 with the aftermarket B-Key keyboard. For those that aren't familiar with the Atari 400, it shipped with a membrane keyboard. Although it was pretty good for being a membrane keyboard, it wasn't as good …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past year I took a chance on an eBay auction that featured an Atari 400 with the aftermarket B-Key keyboard. For those that aren't familiar with the Atari 400, it shipped with a membrane keyboard. Although it was pretty good for being a membrane keyboard, it wasn't as good as a real keyboard. Companies came out with keyboard upgrade kits. The less expensive kits were simply keys with stickers that you placed on top of the membrane keyboard. The best bang for your buck was the B-Key keyboard, which replaced the entire keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My B-Key Atari 400" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/Atari400-blue-2018-12-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The auction didn't state the amount of memory in the 400, but I took a chance that whoever upgraded the keyboard would have upgraded the memory to 48K while the machine was disassembled. Unfortunately, that was not the case. This 400 only has the default 16K of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I ordered the &lt;a href="http://atariage.com/forums/topic/267042-new-hardware-atari-400-ram-card-4852-kb-external-os-rom/"&gt;48/52K upgrade card&lt;/a&gt; from tf_hh over at &lt;a href="http://atariage.com"&gt;AtariAge&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I was planning on using one of Bryan Edwards' UAV kits to add composite/s-video out. That was, until I started looking at the Super Color CPU card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="48/52K upgrade card" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/400ramcard-2018-12-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://atariage.com/forums/topic/260646-new-hardware-atari-400800-super-color-cpu-card/"&gt;Super Color CPU card&lt;/a&gt; is a replacement CPU card for the 400 or 800 line of computers, incorporating Bryan's UAV kit. My Super Color CPU card came in today, and I'm super excited to upgrade my 400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Super Color CPU card" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/supercolorcpucard-2018-12-07-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas break starts in a week and a half, and I can't wait!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="atari400"></category><category term="upgrade"></category></entry><entry><title>Taking RetroPie to the next level with a Lenovo IdeaPad Yoga 11s</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2018/11/25/taking-retropie-to-the-next-level-with-a-lenovo-ideapad-yoga-11s/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-25T20:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T20:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2018-11-25:/2018/11/25/taking-retropie-to-the-next-level-with-a-lenovo-ideapad-yoga-11s/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the Christmas season coming, and knowing that I would be spending time away from home, I struggled with how to bring some retro along with me. In the past I've taken a modded Xbox and a Raspberry Pi to family gatherings, but both of them require me to commandeer …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the Christmas season coming, and knowing that I would be spending time away from home, I struggled with how to bring some retro along with me. In the past I've taken a modded Xbox and a Raspberry Pi to family gatherings, but both of them require me to commandeer one of the TVs, which usually is another boss battle in and of itself. While trying to think of a solution, I spied my Lenovo IdeaPad Yoga 11s, which was my laptop for several years until I replaced it with a Chromebook last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="RetroYoga" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/RetroYoga-2018-11-25-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Yoga has an 11" screen, i5, 8GB of ram and a 256GB SSD. On specs alone it blows the OG Xbox and Raspberry Pi out of the water. More importantly, it had its own screen in addition to HDMI out, which meant I could use it by itself or with a TV, depending on the family temperament. I just needed to get RetroPie installed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Installing Ubuntu 18.04&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several distributions to choose from, and this particular machine ran MATE when I used it as a laptop. I decided to install Ubuntu 18.04, for really no reason in particular. If you're curious on how to install Ubuntu, search around, there is no shortage of installation directions and videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step took less than 15 minutes. After the installation, I was pleasantly surprised that the wireless worked. In the past I had to download and compile the wifi driver, but now it worked out of the box!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up the default user as &lt;em&gt;retro&lt;/em&gt;, with a password of &lt;em&gt;retro&lt;/em&gt;, and automatic log in. This way anyone could start playing without bugging me about passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Installing RetroPie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed the &lt;a href="https://github.com/RetroPie/RetroPie-Setup/wiki/Debian"&gt;instructions in the RetroPie wiki on installing RetroPie under Debian/Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;. It was pretty straightforward, but took forever. This step took a few hours to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the games, I had already downloaded a RetroPie distribution for the Pi and put it on an SD card. I popped the SD card into the built in card reader and dragged the roms to their respective folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Creating a desktop icon&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muggles aren't going to want to start a terminal and type &lt;em&gt;emulationstation&lt;/em&gt; to start up RetroPie, so I created a desktop icon. From a terminal I typed &lt;code&gt;nano ~/Desktop/RetroPie.desktop&lt;/code&gt;. This launched the nano editor, in which I typed the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;#!/usr/bin/env xdg-open&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Desktop&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;1.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Application&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Terminal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Exec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;usr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;bin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;emulationstation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;RetroPie&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Comment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Controllers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fun is playing RetroPie from the keyboard? Not fun at all. I grabbed several controllers I already had and configured them in RetroPie. This included a couple of USB Xbox 360 controllers, and an Xbox One controller connected over USB, and an OG Xbox controller with a USB adapter. I couldn't get RetroPie to recognize my cheap OG Xbox knock off controllers, so I'll have to work on those at a later date. Since the Yoga only has two USB ports, I also grabbed an USB hub. This is only temporary because I would like to get a smaller USB travel hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Traveling case&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To carry the Yoga and controllers to its destination requires a milk crate. I'm going to be looking out for something a little more travel friendly, but this will work for now. The problem is the controllers. They are big and bulky. If I wanted to spend some money I could pick up some travel controllers, but I'm not going to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love a hardshell case which would let me put the Yoga in tablet mode and mount it in the lid while the case holds a wireless keyboard and the controllers, but that's not going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;In Use&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The N64 emulator played Mario Kart 64 flawlessly, with no slowdowns or glitches. Almost all of the games that we played worked well, except for some of the arcade roms, such as Street Fighter II. I'll need to investigate further. One nice feature of using the Yoga is the ability to put the laptop into tablet mode and put it on the side for vertical games such as Frogger and Raiden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Future modifications&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have Atari 8-bit computer functionality, or any retro computer functionality installed. To complete the set up, it would be nice to be able to play Atari 8-bit, Atari ST, and Amiga games. I also need to troubleshoot Street Fighter II.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="retro"></category><category term="raspberrypi"></category><category term="retropie"></category></entry><entry><title>Two LCD VGA monitors that work with my Amiga 500</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2018/11/09/two-lcd-vga-monitors-that-work-with-my-amiga-500/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-09T20:37:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-09T20:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2018-11-09:/2018/11/09/two-lcd-vga-monitors-that-work-with-my-amiga-500/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nec Multisync 1970VX" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/IMG_5794-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased a Nec Multisync 1970VX VGA monitor for use on my older RGB computers (Atari ST/STE/Amiga/CoCo 3/800XL with VBXE). It works well with the Amiga. Unfortunately, I can't get it to show up with my Mega STe. I haven't tried it with any of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nec Multisync 1970VX" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/IMG_5794-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased a Nec Multisync 1970VX VGA monitor for use on my older RGB computers (Atari ST/STE/Amiga/CoCo 3/800XL with VBXE). It works well with the Amiga. Unfortunately, I can't get it to show up with my Mega STe. I haven't tried it with any of my other STs, but I'm thinking that the cable may not be right. I ordered a cable from Best and will try it after it arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen looks really good with the Amiga 500 though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year or so ago I purchased a Nec Accusync LCD 71V after reading it was compatible with the 15KHz refresh of these older computers. At the time I couldn't get a machine to work with it, so I assumed it wouldn't. Well, I tried it again and it worked with the Amiga. I have no idea what I was doing wrong before. I prefer the 1970VX though, since it is a 19" screen vs the 17" of the 71V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm beginning to miss CRTs. Hopefully, in the future, scan doublers and upscalers will take advantage of the higher resolution screens that are available, making the CRT discussion moot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="amiga"></category><category term="monitor"></category><category term="vga"></category></entry><entry><title>Continuing playing around with the VT420</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2018/10/23/continuing-playing-around-with-the-vt420/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-23T19:53:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-23T19:53:00+02:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2018-10-23:/2018/10/23/continuing-playing-around-with-the-vt420/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've got everything working pretty well, with only a few nagging 
problems. The biggest is the screen corrupting of vim when running 
through tmux. The problem is there with screen also. If I use vim 
outside of tmux or screen, it works fine. Inside of tmux or screen? 
Problems. :-( Maybe …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've got everything working pretty well, with only a few nagging 
problems. The biggest is the screen corrupting of vim when running 
through tmux. The problem is there with screen also. If I use vim 
outside of tmux or screen, it works fine. Inside of tmux or screen? 
Problems. :-( Maybe it's a sign to not multitask when writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've grown accustomed to using multiple programs at the command line, if 
I can't get vim to work, I guess I can use something like nano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, I switched to nano, and am using it within tmux. So far, so good, 
although I'm already missing the spell check as I type which I had set 
up in vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will work for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vt420"></category></entry><entry><title>Trying out my VT420</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2018/10/22/trying-out-my-vt420/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-22T20:37:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T20:37:00+02:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2018-10-22:/2018/10/22/trying-out-my-vt420/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VT420" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/IMG_5687-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up a couple of DEC VT420 terminals from a school auction about 
20 years ago. Unfortunately, I never did anything with them because I 
didn't have any way to hook them up. The VT420 terminal uses an MMJ 
connector, which kind of looks like an RJ11 (phone connector …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VT420" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2018/IMG_5687-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up a couple of DEC VT420 terminals from a school auction about 
20 years ago. Unfortunately, I never did anything with them because I 
didn't have any way to hook them up. The VT420 terminal uses an MMJ 
connector, which kind of looks like an RJ11 (phone connector) except 
that the clip is off center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I ordered a cable from Pacific Custom Cable and bought a 
couple of MMJ to DB25 adapters off of eBay. Now I have the terminal 
plugged into my Portmaster terminal server and I can computer like it's 
1989.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vt420"></category></entry><entry><title>First post from my iMac G4</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2017/04/24/first-post-from-my-imac-g4/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-24T15:37:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-04-24T15:37:00+02:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2017-04-24:/2017/04/24/first-post-from-my-imac-g4/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test post from my iMac G4 running Leopard from an SSD drive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ppc"></category><category term="powerpc"></category><category term="g4"></category><category term="imacg4"></category></entry><entry><title>I should have bought a mono VGA cable for my MegaSTE a long time ago</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2016/03/05/i-should-have-bought-a-mono-vga-cable-for-my-megaste-a-long-time-ago/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-05T19:33:22+01:00</published><updated>2016-03-05T19:33:22+01:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2016-03-05:/2016/03/05/i-should-have-bought-a-mono-vga-cable-for-my-megaste-a-long-time-ago/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago I went in the hunt for a better monitor for my MegaSTE and ended up using my old Gateway 2000 monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2016/IMG_9686.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't let the GW2k name fool you, this is a 15" Sony Trinitron monitor, capable of 1024x768 at 75Hz. It was a pretty sweet …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago I went in the hunt for a better monitor for my MegaSTE and ended up using my old Gateway 2000 monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new setup" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2016/IMG_9686.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't let the GW2k name fool you, this is a 15" Sony Trinitron monitor, capable of 1024x768 at 75Hz. It was a pretty sweet monitor back in 1994, and still is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer the CRT, especially since I can adjust the screen to fill it up and the lower 640x400 resolution doesn't look as blocky as it does when using an LCD. I did try out a Dell 20" 4:3 LCD that I use with my retrocomputers, but it wouldn't expand out the image to fill the screen. The Gateway monitor looks sweet anyway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With everyone moving to LCDs, I wonder if I can find a VGA CRT that will sync with the Atari models...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>VBXE and Ultimate 1MB success!</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2015/12/29/vbxe-and-ultimate-1mb-success/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-29T18:41:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-29T18:41:00+01:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2015-12-29:/2015/12/29/vbxe-and-ultimate-1mb-success/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After several hours of troubleshooting and beating on it, I'm proud to show off my successful installation of the VBXE along with an Ultimate 1M:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Success" src="//cdn.gtia.com/pics/2015/IMG_9081-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels weird using the 800XL on an VGA LCD screen, almost like I'm in emulation. To convert the VBXE output to VGA I'm using …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After several hours of troubleshooting and beating on it, I'm proud to show off my successful installation of the VBXE along with an Ultimate 1M:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Success" src="//cdn.gtia.com/pics/2015/IMG_9081-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels weird using the 800XL on an VGA LCD screen, almost like I'm in emulation. To convert the VBXE output to VGA I'm using an GBS-8200 converter, which does a really good job of it. The monitor I'm using is a 15" Magnavox TV that is also a VGA monitor. It's nice because I can use the built in speakers for sound. I may start cruising eBay for another Dell 20" lcd though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vbxe"></category><category term="u1m"></category></entry><entry><title>VBXE to GBS-8200 to VGA monitor is a success</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2015/12/28/vbxe-to-gbs-8200-to-vga-monitor-is-a-success/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-28T23:22:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-28T23:22:00+01:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2015-12-28:/2015/12/28/vbxe-to-gbs-8200-to-vga-monitor-is-a-success/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After much troubleshooting, I now have VGA output from an 800XL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VBXE in Action" src="//cdn.gtia.com/pics/2015/IMG_9078-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VBXE plugs into the 5 pin connector on the GBS-8200, which then goes out as VGA. Unfortunately, the Apple monitor doesn't have a VGA plug, so I have an adapter to convert it. Looks very good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After much troubleshooting, I now have VGA output from an 800XL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="VBXE in Action" src="//cdn.gtia.com/pics/2015/IMG_9078-2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VBXE plugs into the 5 pin connector on the GBS-8200, which then goes out as VGA. Unfortunately, the Apple monitor doesn't have a VGA plug, so I have an adapter to convert it. Looks very good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to install a Ultimate 1MB and the stereo upgrade...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vbxe"></category><category term="vga"></category></entry><entry><title>The original Xbox is an awesome emulator machine</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2014/11/15/the-xbox-is-an-awesome-emulator-machine/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-15T13:45:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-11-15T13:45:00+01:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2014-11-15:/2014/11/15/the-xbox-is-an-awesome-emulator-machine/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I modded my Xbox a long time ago, and over the years forgot about it, leaving the Xbox to sit on the bottom shelf. It waited patiently for years until I stumbled across a post on AtariAge about using the Xbox with emulators that piqued my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon firing up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I modded my Xbox a long time ago, and over the years forgot about it, leaving the Xbox to sit on the bottom shelf. It waited patiently for years until I stumbled across a post on AtariAge about using the Xbox with emulators that piqued my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon firing up the Xbox, I was surprised that it was still functional. Well, sort of. It usually took a few tries to fire up. I installed a larger hard drive in it and grabbed AtariXLBox from &lt;a href="http://xport.xbox-scene.com/"&gt;Xport&lt;/a&gt; along with a bunch of A8 games in various formats. It was able to play all of them without a hitch. In fact, with the Xbox plugged into a CRT TV, it was pretty much indistinguishable from the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a big emulation person, I’d rather be playing on the real thing, but using an Xbox has it’s advantages. For one, I can easily take it places and play several systems on it (there are emulators for all of the major consoles and arcade). It doesn’t support the multi-joy adapter from what I’ve seen, but I should be able to set up the 3rd joypad to work as the third player in Dynakillers. Lastly, it does support saving the settings on a game-by-game basis which makes it easier to start games up without worrying about what hardware the game requires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be relatively inexpensive to try out this route. An original Xbox usually goes for under $50 on eBay, but if you look at garage sales or Craigslist you can probably find it cheaper. You’ll need to do some research on how to mod the Xbox so you can run the emulators. This usually involves using certain games with certain save files that trick the Xbox into running unsigned code. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="xbox"></category><category term="emulation"></category></entry><entry><title>Fired up my Colecovision Adam for the first time</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2014/05/12/fired-up-my-colecovision-adam-for-the-first-time/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-12T11:56:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-05-12T11:56:00+02:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2014-05-12:/2014/05/12/fired-up-my-colecovision-adam-for-the-first-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At some time I picked up a Colecovision Adam (complete) with several books and datapacks. I was disappointed Donkey Kong wasn't in the box, but Donkey Kong Jr. was. As I was cleaning and arranging my basement lab, I decided I had better at least try out the Colecovision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At some time I picked up a Colecovision Adam (complete) with several books and datapacks. I was disappointed Donkey Kong wasn't in the box, but Donkey Kong Jr. was. As I was cleaning and arranging my basement lab, I decided I had better at least try out the Colecovision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first turn it on, you are put into some sort of typewriter mode. I don't have a ribbon in the printer, and the print head didn't like being turned on. Eventually, the printer stopped jamming the print head to the side, and I could type in the typewriter. I then switched it to word processing mode. Unless I'm missing something, this mode was terrible. This came out the same year as AtariWriter was released, and it doesn't even have full screen editing. I would have hated to actually use this to word process. That is, unless I'm missing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was to try out the data packs. They look like normal audio cassettes, but work like the tape back up drives I used to use at work. I put Donkey Kong into the unity, and hit the reset slider besides the cartridge port (luckily I had the manual :-). And there I was playing DK Jr! Unfortunately, while it looks good, it doesn't play very much like the original. The chomping creatures (I'm sure they have a name) move too slow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I'm glad to have a piece of history, and will be happy to put this into my future antique electronics store!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="colecovision"></category><category term="adam"></category></entry><entry><title>Upgraded a XF551 disk drive to a 3.5" drive</title><link href="https://gtia.com/2014/05/05/upgraded-a-xf551-disk-drive-to-a-35-drive/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-05T13:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2014-05-05T13:03:13+02:00</updated><author><name>gozar</name></author><id>tag:gtia.com,2014-05-05:/2014/05/05/upgraded-a-xf551-disk-drive-to-a-35-drive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 90s I purchased a large Atari collection on eBay. It's been sitting in storage, just waiting for me to dig into it. I remember I bough it for the Spartados X cartridge and R-time 8, but didn't realize everything else that was in it. I found …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 90s I purchased a large Atari collection on eBay. It's been sitting in storage, just waiting for me to dig into it. I remember I bough it for the Spartados X cartridge and R-time 8, but didn't realize everything else that was in it. I found an XF551 case which apparently had a CSS 3.5" upgrade kit installed. After stealing a 3.5" drive mechanism from an old PC, I was able to format my first 3.5" disk on my trusty Atari 800XL! (Actually, it took me 4 tries to find a disk that would format. I was using an ST to format a disk first to make sure it wasn't the upgrade causing the formatting to fail.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't know what I'm going to use floppy disks for, but it is still pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My XF351!" src="http://cdn.gtia.com/2014/xf551-3.5-l.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="xf551"></category><category term="diskdrive"></category></entry></feed>